A spine-chilling ghost story
The Woman in Black is a horror, mystery, tv movie film directed by Herbert Wise.
A lawyer travels to a small seaside town to settle the estate of a recently deceased
woman, but soon becomes ensnared in something much more sinister.
Arthur Kidd, played by Adrian Rawlins.
Sam Toovey, played by Bernard Hepton.
Josiah Freston, played by David Daker.
Woman in Black, played by Pauline Moran.
Sweetman, played by David Ryall.
Stella Kidd, played by Clare Holman.
The Woman in Black is a 1989 British horror drama television film directed by Herbert Wise
and starring Adrian Rawlins, Bernard Hepton, David Daker and Pauline Moran.
The teleplay is adapted from the 1983 novel of the same name by Susan Hill.
It focuses on a young solicitor who is sent to a coastal English village to
settle the estate of a reclusive widow, and finds the town haunted.
The programme was produced by Central Independent Television
for ITV, and premiered on Christmas Eve 1989.
It was an unexpected success, though author Susan Hill reportedly disagreed with some
of the slight changes screenwriter Nigel Kneale made in the adaptation.
Another film version, starring Daniel Radcliffe, was released in 2012.
The film explores themes of based on novel or
book, haunted house, gothic horror.
The tone is dark and mind_bending.